Guide to the Washington Wool Growers Association Women's Auxiliary Records 1923-2004
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Washington Wool Growers Association Women's Auxiliary Records
1923-2004
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Cage 844
Washington Wool Growers Association. Women's Auxilary
2 linear feet of shelf space 4 boxes
Records of the Women's Auxiliary of the Washington Wool Growers Association. Includes minutes, correspondence, constitutions and by-laws, membership lists, financial reports, conference programs, photographs, newspaper clippings and other printed material.
The Women's Auxiliary of the Washington Wool Growers Association was founded in 1923 to bring together wives of members of the association, and over time the membership was broadened to include women interested in the industries and activities represented in the association. Promoting sheep products with a variety of activities and events, the group sponsors "Make It Yourself with Wool," an annual sewing contest, and raises funds for its activities with a Lamburger booth at the Central Washington Fair. They support agricultural education and training for youth, including 4-H and Future Farmers of America members involved in projects related to sheep and wool.
The Washington Wool Growers Association is an organization of sheep producers and wool growers in the state of Washington. The state association is a branch of the National Wool Growers Association.
The membership of the Washington Wool Growers Association consists of persons who are both directly involved in the production of sheep and wool and those who are within the sheep industry or have an interest in it. The goals of the Association are to promote the welfare of the sheep industry in the state of Washington and to promote consumer usage of wool and lamb. They accomplish this by working on and/or lobbying for Congressional bills concerning foreign imports of sheep products, livestock taxes, public lands usage and predator control. Wool and lamb consumption are boosted through yearly barbeques which make people more aware of lamb and its many uses and through annual state and national Miss Wool contests. Miss Wool is a public relations representative for the industry.
This collection consists of records of the Women's Auxiliary of the Washington Wool Growers Association. It includes minutes, correspondence, constitutions and by-laws, membership lists, financial reports, conference programs, photographs, newspaper clippings and other printed material. Most of the folders include a cover sheet summarizing the contents, which vary from year to year, and some have notes about the year's officers and important activities. Some of the folders have fairly extensive documentation of the group's activities for the year, while others contain just an item or two.
This collection is arranged in a single series, in chronological order with just a few exceptions.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Helen Appel donated this collection to the Washington State University Libraries on behalf of the Washington Wool Growers Association Women's Auxiliary in 2016 (MS.2016.19).
Washington Wool Growers Association Records, 1950-1970 (Cage 439)
Washington Wool Growers Association Records, 1969-1979 (Cage 523)
Preliminary Guide to the Washington Wool Growers Association Records, 1987-2008 (MS 2016.20)
Columbia Basin Wool Growers Association Records, 1955-1976 (Cage 359)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington Wool Growers Association. Women's Auxiliary -- Records and correspondence; Washington Wool Growers Association -- Records and correspondence
Women in agriculture; Sheep -- Washington (State); Wool industry -- Washington (State); Agriculture -- Washington (State) -- Societies, etc. -- Records and correspondence
Women; Agriculture; Washington (State)
- 1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1931 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Minute book, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
- 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 1933 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- 1938 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- 1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- 1940 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- 1941 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Conventions and committees, and chapter reports, 1942-1947 (Box 1, Folder 21-23)
- 1943 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- 1944 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- 1945 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- 1946 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- 1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- 1948 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Photographs, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- 1951 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 1953 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 1954 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 1955 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- 1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 1957 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Check register, 1958-1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- 1960 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- 1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- 1963 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- 1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
- 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- 1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- 1968 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous, 1974-1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- 1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Minutes, 1981-1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- 1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- 1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- 1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- 1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- 1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- 1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- 1990 (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
- 1991 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- 1992 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- 1993 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- 1994 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- 1995 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- 1996 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- 1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- 1998 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- 1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- 2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- 2001 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- 2002 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
- 2003 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
- 2004 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
- Undated (circa 1960-1973) (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous (photographs, clippings, pamphlets, conference badges), circa 1929-1990s (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Beulah Hill notebook, 1929-1949. Includes information about the formation of the national women's auxiliary organization. (Box 4, Folder 13)